# 今天我伯爷在街上买了一套牛鞭
My uncle bought a bull pizzle on the street
# 但是他不会弄
But he doesn't know how to cook it
# 正好我现在有时间
Since I have some time right now...
# 然后我做一顿饭给大家吃
Gonna cook this thing for everyone to enjoy
# 四伯爷一会儿这个整（做）辣的哦
Uncle how'bout cook the pizzle with chili?
# 当然要整辣的哦
Sure thing!
# 不整辣的不好吃
Pizzle won't taste good without chili
# 要越辣越好
The more spicy, the better
# 晓得
Got it!
# 辣椒多放点 七星椒多放点整辣一点
Add more chili, especially Qixing Jiao(Seven Star Pepper) which enhances the spiciness
# 不是压不住那个腥味
Or you ain't cover the odor
# 这个应该是我伯爷冻了2天的
My uncle probably froze this for several days
# 这个要新鲜的才好吃 不过冻1-2天也没没关系
Only fresh pizzle tastes good, but a short time in the fridge won't matter that much after all
# 等一下要焯完水再把这个撕掉
Blanching first, then we can peel this part off
# 里面再花开洗一下
cut it open to wash the interior
# 姜 蒜
Ginger & Garlic
# 蒜一会儿再弄
Well, gonna come back to prepare the garlics
# 漆二娃
Qierwa
# 哎
Yes?
# 过来烧火
Can you start the fire for us?
# 来了
Coming now!
# 我们先把这个方下去焯下水
Throw it in the wok for blanching
# 焯完水再慢慢洗
After that we can wash it thoroughly
# 其实这个东西女性吃了对身体也不错 并不是说只有男性可以吃
Actually it's good for women's body as well despite being labeled as a masculine food
# 现在这个焯好水了我们把它捞出来洗一下再清理一会儿
Alright it's done blanching, let's drain the water and take some time to clean it
# 其实这个还是缩水缩得蛮厉害的
It shrinks quite a bit
# 那么大一个缩来还剩那么一点点
There is only a fraction of it left comparing to its size before
# 你看
See
# 现在我们把这个切一下 再拿到外面去清洗
Let's cut it before taking out for the final sanitation
# 好烫
It's so hot
# 这个要把油撕一下
Peel the fat off
# 然后这个筋也要撕掉 要不然很腥臭
And also clean the connective tissues which makes the pizzle stinky
# 把牛鞭宰成小节备用
Cut the pizzle into small segments, set aside
# 用花刀把牛宝切成小块备用
Cut the testicle into small dices, and set aside
# 蒜苗斜刀切成小段备用
Tilt the knife and cut the garlic sprouts into small segments, set aside
# 准备火锅底料一小块切碎备用
Dice a small chunk of hot pot condiment, set aside
# 准备生姜2小块拍散之后剁碎备用
Slap the ginger with knife and mince it, set aside
# 准备适量的大蒜切成小粒备用
Finely dice some garlics and set aside
# 2颗八角1小块桂皮
Prepare 2 star anises and some cinnamon bark
# 生抽酱油
Also prepare some light soy sauce
# 哟 还是四伯得行（厉害）
Ayo, It is uncle that can do this after all
# 我是烧火的老手
I am a fire-making veteran
# 漆二娃整半天都没烧然
Qierwa took her time yet still fail to start the fire
# 这个（牛鞭）再焯一下水
(The pizzle) needs more blanching
# 不是害怕你吃起有味道所以再焯一下水
I'm blanching it again, in case you feel any odor
# 佐料还要齐全
Make sure that you got all the seasonings
# 东西要真刻（质量要好） 不是的那种歪货
Use quality stuff instead of those cheap knock off
# 要好货 这个是好东西哦
You need good stuff, and this is exactly what you need
# 拿给你买对了的
I hand-picked the appropriate ones
# 四伯爷这段时间猪肉涨得好凶啊
Uncle did you know that pork price skyrocketed recently
# 涨得凶得很
ye, exponential increases
# 成都 重庆猪肉卖35元1斤
Port sells at 35 yuan per jin in Chen Du, Chong Qiu
# 好多呀
How much?
# 35元1斤
35 yuan per jin(250g)
# 那这样你这两天都没卖肉哦
But I did not see you selling port these days?
# 没有卖肉在耍
No
# 等赚钱的时候再买
Gonna do when it makes money
# 锅烧辣点哦
Make it spicy, remember
# 我放油了
Adding oil now
# 放嘛
Do it
# 放点宽油哦
I'm dropping my "Kuan You"(lit lots of oil)
# 放嘛 不放宽油这东西不好吃
Sure, pizzle needs Kuan You
# 多放点花椒哦
Add more Sichuan Peppercorn as well
# 肯定要多放点花椒撒
Definitely
# 好嘛
Alright
# 花椒辣椒都要放多一点 这样才压得到腥味
Add more chili n. paper to cover the odor
# 泡辣椒我放得多哦
I also put quite a lot of picked chili
# 这个放得麻辣麻辣的安逸点撒
Spicy and numbing is the best taste profile for this dish
# 我是拿的火锅底料来烧的
I used hot pot condiments for seasoning
# 可以
Good
# 火烧小一点 四伯爷
Lowering the heat, uncle
# 嗯 都闻到香了
Emm, already smiling the fragrance
# 还是要宽油的质量好
You need quality Kuan You to cook the dish
# 宽油的质量不好随笔阿尼怎么炒都没得香味得
You don't get the the fragrance no matter how hard you try unless you use good Kuan You
# 为什么我自己榨的宽油10块钱1斤好买呀
That's why I can sell my Kuan You well at the price of 10 yuan per Jin
# 就是这个道理
It is just that!
# 诶呀
oops
# 还多辣
So spicy
# 嗯
Yeah
# 烧小火吗
Low heat?
# 烧中小火
Mid-low heat
# 盖上烧20分钟就差不多了
20 minutes would be enough cooking it with the lid on
# 我们现在这个已经焖了差不多40分钟了
Well we actually have braised it for nearly 40 minutes
# 因为在20分钟的时候我吃了一下
I tried it at the 20 minutes point
# 我倒是嚼得动我怕我伯爷嚼不动所以多焖了一会儿
I can chew through but I was afraid that my uncle won't make it, so I braised it for some extra time
# 40分钟之后就可以
After 40 minutes...
# xxx
(Inaudible)
# 然后准备了一些蒜苗放在锅里面垫底
I prepared some garlic sprouts to lay on the bottom of the pot
# 这个是生蒜苗
These are raw
# 因为待会儿下面还会放火继续加热
Because we are suppose to heat it on the stove again later
# 这个菜非常适合冬天吃
This dish is suitable for winter
# 然后我先把味调了
Let me get the seasoning done first
# 因为我放了火锅底料所以只放酱油就行了
We only need to add soy sauce since I used hot pot condiments
# 然后把蒜苗放进去
Then put the garlic sprouts in
# 蒜苗放进去把它烧熟就OK
It's an OK when garlic sprouts are cooked
# 好啦 我们起锅
Alright, ready to serve
# 最后味道肯定很爽
It must be a tasty dish!
# 我们下面这个放了碳
The stove at bottom is filled with charcoal
# 然后这个放在上面慢慢烧
which heats up the dish on the top slowly
# 边吃边烧
while we are eating
# 我们先吃
We can start eating now
# 伯娘在炒青菜
Aunt is cooking some greens
# 这个牛鞭可能一般人不会弄
There are few people who can cook pizzle properly
# 其实这个很简单
It is actually quite simple
# 吃撒 四伯爷
Try it! Uncle
# 我试一下你的手艺
Let me check on your skills
# 然后我放了火锅底料来烧这个
Then I used hot pot condiments to cook the dish
# 就没有放盐加了一点酱油就可以了
So I did not add any extra salt but only a bit of soy sauce
# 然后放了大蒜、泡椒、生姜
After that you add garlics, pickled chili, ginger
# 下面垫了一些蒜苗
And laying some garlic sprouts for the final step
# 因为它会慢慢煮嘛
Those sprouts will get slowly cooked
# 它会越煮越香
which increases the flavor during the process
# 耶 这个东西又辣又麻哟
Wow, it's both spicy and numbing
# 吃点啊
Try it?
# 我等伯娘炒好菜我再吃
I'm waiting for Auntie to finish cooking the greens
# 又麻又辣
Spicy and numbing
# 嗯
Yeah
# 跟麻辣火锅一样
Almost like "Mala Hot Pot"
# 请大家不要对这个菜有什么误解
Everyone please don't misinterpret pizzle as a soup-only ingredient
# 它除了可以煲汤之外
You can use it to make soup
# 还可以这样烧 烧成香辣的或者不辣的
Other than that, you can braise it with chili or without chili
# 都可以
All good
# 其实大家都说 男性吃了这个菜很好
The general conception is that pizzle is good for man
# 其实女性吃了也很不错
While in truth it is also good for woman to have
# 好啦 今天就到这里我们要吃饭了
Alright, this is it for today because it's dining time for us
# 你就等一会儿吃青菜哦
So apparently all you will eat is greens?
# 好
Exactly